Inventory of the Charles Campbell Papers 1743-1896
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Charles Campbell Papers, 1743-1896.
Special Collections, Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
Mss. 65 C17
5,146 items.
Papers received or collected by Charles Campbell (1807-1876), Virginia Historian, as well as letters and other papers, 1743-1896. Includes the business correspondence of Charles Campbell with various editors of The Southern Literary Messenger, several historical societies, publishing firms, historians and authors, with Petersburg, Virginia. Items also relate to organizations and institutions with which he was affiliated, to the school that he conducted in Petersburg and to his personal correspondence with friends and members of his family. Diaries and notebooks both kept by Charles Campbell and his wife Anna Burdsall Campbell, plus 18 scrapbooks, autographs, historical notes, etc. are also found in the collection.
George Bancroft,; Henry Barnard,; Nathaniel Francis Cabell,; Anna Burdsall Campbell,; Calloway Campbell,; Charles Campbell,; Mildred Walker Moore Campbell,; Mary B. Carter,; William Alexander Caruthers,; John Esten Cooke,; Charles Deane,; Lyman Copeland Draper,; Henry Dilworth Gilpin,; Hugh Blair Grigsby,; William Wirt Henry,; Henry Howe,; Benson John Lossing,; Edmund Ruffin,; Campbell Family.
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Collection is open to all researchers.
Acquisition Information
Purchased: 5,144 items, 10/23/1942.
Gift: 1 item, 06/01/1977.
Gift: 1 item, 06/25/1992.
Biographical/Historical Information
Charles Campbell (1807-1876) was born on 1 May 1807, in Petersburg, Virginia, the firstborn child of parents John Wilson Campbell (d.1842), and Mildred Walker Moore Campbell. John, a bookstore owner, was also a historian. In 1831 he published the History of Virginia to 1781. Later, he held the position of Federal Collector of Customs in Petersburg, Virginia. Mildred taught at the Petersburg Classical Academy in the 1840's. In addition to Charles, the couple also had two younger children, Alexander (Aleck) S. Campbell, and Elizabeth (Betty) Campbell Maben (d.1871).
Charles' mother, Mildred Walker Moore Campbell, was the granddaughter of Virginia lieutenant governor Alexander Spotswood (1676-1740). Mildred Walker Moore Campbell and her siblings Mary Fairfax Moore Keller, Dr. Alexander Spotswood Moore, Ann Evelina Moore Henley, William Agustin Moore, Eliza Moore McDonald, and Lavinia Moore McPheeters wrote and received numerous pieces of personal correspondence that are available in this collection.
Charles Campbell attended the College of New Jersey (later Princeton University) from 1823-1825. Upon graduation he enrolled in Henry St. George Tucker's School of Law in Winchester, Virginia. However, he suffered from chronic headaches which caused him severe physical and mental exhaustion. By 1829, these health issues would force him to leave the law profession.
Following his departure from law, Campbell worked as an engineer of the Petersburg Railroad. Later he ran a private school for boys in Glencoe, Alabama. On 13 September 1836, he married Elvira N. Callaway (1819-1837) of Monroe County, Tennessee. In 1837, Elvira died shortly after the birth of a son, Callaway Campbell (b.1837). In his distress, Campbell left his son with Elivira's siblings, Thomas and Lucinda Callaway. Later, this would result in a court case to regain custody of his child.
Following the death of his wife, Campbell worked as a clerk in the office of the Collector of Custom in Petersburg, Virginia (a position he obtained from his father John Campbell). From 1840-1843, Campbell also owned, published, and edited a Petersburg newspaper, The American Statesman. He returned to teaching in 1842 by opening a classical school in Petersburg, becoming both teacher and administrator in the Anderson Seminary. He would hold these positions until the formation of free public schools in 1870.
Campbell remarried in 1850 to Miss Anna Birdsall of Rahway, New Jersey. They had four children, Mary Spotswood Campbell Robinson (b.1852), Nanny Campbell (b.1854), Charles Campbell (b.1856), and Fanny Campbell (1858-1860's).
Charles Campbell was committed to Western Lunatic Asylum at Staunton, Virginia, in 1873 where he remained until his death on July 11, 1876. He was buried at Blandford Church Cemetery, Petersburg.
Like his father, Campbell was a historian. He began contributing to journals in 1834. Some of the journals to which he frequently contributed included; The Southern Literary Messenger or The Southern and Western Literary Messenger and Review; The Farmer's Register; The New Yorker; and the Petersburg Intelligencer. His most important work, however, was the History of the Colony and Ancient Dominion of Virginia. This work built upon his father's book and concerned Virginia history from the colony's founding to the Revolutionary War.
Scope and Content Information
The Charles Campbell papers consist of papers received or collected by Charles Campbell (1807-1876) Virginia historian. The papers fall into four general headings: historical papers collected by Charles Campbell, correspondence, manuscript volumes, and miscellaneous. These include personal and professional correspondence as well as eighteenth century documents collected by Charles Campbell, newspaper clippings, diaries, scrapbooks, and notebooks, covering then period 1743-1896. The papers reflect Charles Campbell's interests in history, teaching, newspaper editing, railroad engineering, politics, genealogy, publication of his works, and the town of Petersburg where he lived for most of his life.
The personal papers include Charles Campbell's correspondence with his father John Wilson Campbell, brother Alexander Campbell, sister, wife and children as well as cousins in Tennessee, Alabama, and Virginia. These include copies of Charles Campbell's letters, as well as letters received by him; biographical material; genealogical material; autograph collecting material; and letters received by Charles Campbell's second wife Anna Burdsall Campbell. These also include correspondence relating to organizations with which he was affiliated, such as the Petersburg Library and the Petersburg Lyceum.
His professional correspondence consists of letters to the editors of the Southern Literary Messenger, to historical societies, to publishing firms, and to other historians and authors. The writing, publishing and critic of Charles Campbell's book Virginia History, concerns much of these material. Charles Campbell also corresponded with genealogists and antiquarians interested in Virginia history.
The eighteenth century documents collected by Charles Campbell include letters by John Quarles, John Byrd, George Dabney, William Degge, Edward Hill, John Jameson, Alexander Moore, William Aylett, and Theodorick Bland, as well as parts of William Aylett's account books (1770-1776).
The manuscript volumes include Charles Campbell's diaries (1861-1864), Anna Burdsall Campbell diaries (1840-1870), scrapbooks, Charles Campbell's historical notes, newspaper clippings, Anderson Seminary account books, Charles Campbell's pupil exercise books, pamphlets, copies of Charles Campbell's articles, and household account books (1848-1863).
There are many letters from Mary B. Carter of "Shirley," Charles City County, Virginia to Mildred Walker (Moore) Campbell, Charles Campbell's mother.
Arrangement
Organization
This collection is organized into five series. Series 1 contains historical manuscripts; Series 2 contains family and professional papers; Series 3 contains manuscript volumes; Series 4 contains miscellaneous material; and Series 5 contains the addition 1992.33b.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into series and then chronologically by date. Series 3, containing family and professional papers, is arranged into subseries by decade and then into additional subseries by individual year.
Additional Related and Bibliographic Material
Bibliography
Beverley, Robert. The history of Virginia, in four parts. By Robert Beverley, a native and inhabitant of the place. Reprinted from the author's 2d rev. ed., London, 1722. With an introduction by Charles Campbell.Richmond: J. W. Randolph ..., 1855.
Available as printed book and as microform, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: F229 .B59
Bland, Theodorick. The Bland Papers. Edited by Charles Campbell. Petersburg: E. & J. Ruffin, 1840.
Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number:E263 .V8 B6
Campbell, Charles. The Diary of Charles Campbell, October 5, 1861-April 5, 1862. Edited by Marian Lois Moran. 1966.
Master's Thesis, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: LD6051 .W5m Hist., 1966, M67
Campbell, Charles. Genealogy of the Spotswood Family in Scotland and Virginia.Albany: J. Munsell, 1868.
Available as microfiche, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: F226 .B96
Campbell, Charles. History of the Colony and Ancient Dominion of Virginia. Philadelphia, Lippincott, 1860.Spartanburg: Reprint Co., 1965.
Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: F229 .C18 1860a
Campbell, Charles. History of the Colony and Ancient Dominion of Virginia.Philadelphia: J. B. Lippincott and Co., 1860.
Manuscript and Rare Book Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: F229 .C182
Campbell, Charles. Introduction to the History of the Colony and Ancient Dominion of Virginia.Richmond: B. B. Minor, 1847.
Manuscripts and Rare Book Department, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: F229 .C17
Campbell, Charles, ed. Some Material to serve for a brief memoir of John Daly Burk, author of a History of Virginia. With a sketch of the life and character of his only child, Judge John Junius Burk.Albany: J. Munsell, 1868.
Available as printed book and as microform, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: F226 .B96
Cryer, William Howell. Charles Campbell: early life and works (1807-1847). 1947.
Master's Thesis, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: LD6051 .W5m Hist., 1947, C79
Jefferson, Isaac. Memoirs of a Monticello slave, as dictated to Charles Campbell in the 1840's by Isaac, one of Thomas Jefferson's slaves. Edited by Sarah Dean Link. Charlottesville: University of Virginia Press, c1951.
Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: E444 .J4 1951a
Virginia Infantry. 6th Regiment, 1776-1778. The orderly book of that portion of the American army stationed at or near Williamsburg, Va., under the command of General Andrew Lewis, from March 18th, 1776, to August 28th, 1776 Virginia Infantry. 6th Regiment, 1776-1778. Printed from the original manuscript, with notes and introduction by Charles Campbell, esq. ...Richmond: Priv. print, 1860.
Available as printed book and as microform, Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: E263 .V8 V74
Wyatt, Edward Avery. Charles Campbell, Virginia's 'Old Mortality.' Southern Sketches no.5 1st series. Charlottesville: The Historical Publishing Co., Inc., 1935.
Swem Library, College of William and Mary.
Call Number: E444 .J4 1951a
Index to Materials
The following index contains an alphabetical overview of key correspondents and manuscript volumes. These selected people are historians, editors, and authors that either wrote to or received materials from Charles Campell.
Bancroft, George (1800-1891)
George Bancroft, Boston, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 25 March 1840. Box-folder: 4:8.
George Bancroft, Boston, to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 27 July 1840. Box-folder: 4:21.
George Bancroft, Boston, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 14 May 1844. Box-folder: 4:146.
[Charles Campbell, Petersburg], to [George Bancroft], [before 5 May 1846]. Box-folder: 5:113.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to George Bancroft, 5 May 1846. Box-folder: 5:114.
George Bancroft, Washington, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 8 May 1846. Box-folder: 5:118.
George Bancroft, Washington, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 16 July 1846. Box-folder: 5:137.
George Bancroft, New York, to [Charles Campbell?], 23 April 1860. Box-folder: 12:45.
Barnard, Henry (1811-1900)
H[enry] Barnard, New Haven, Connecticut, to Mildred W. Campbell, Petersburg, 23 December 1833. Box- folder: 2:46.
[Charles Campbell], Somerville, Alabama, to Henry Barnard, 7 February 1835. Box-folder: 3:7.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to [Henry] Barnard, 2 November 1836. Box-folder: 3:66.
Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to Charles Campbell, 12 November 1836. Box-folder: 3:67.
Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to Charles Campbell, 3 July. 1839. Box-folder: 3:137.
Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to Charles Campbell, 30 May 1843. Box-folder: 4:102.
Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to [Charles Campbell], 2 January 1844. Box-folder: 4:125.
H[enry] Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to Charles Campbell, 14 April 1846. Box-folder: 5:106.
Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to [Charles Campbell], [Petersburg], 14 June 1846. Box-folder: 5:128.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Henry Barnard, 26 June 1846. Box-folder: 5:131.
H[enry] Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to [Charles Campbell], 5 August 1846. Box-folder: 6:4.
Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], to Henry Barnard, [Hartford], 9 August 1846. Box-folder: 6:5.
Henry Barnard, Providence, Rhode Island, to Charles Campbell, 24 September 1846. Box-folder: 6:16.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to [Henry] Barnard, 26 September 1846. Box-folder: 6:17.
Henry Barnard, Charleston, South Carolina, to Charles Campbell, 18 April 1848. Box-folder: 7:31.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Henry Barnard, 20 April 1848. Box-folder: 7:32.
Henry Barnard, [Murfreesboro], South Carolina, to C[harles] Campbell, [Petersburg], 5 May 1848. Box-folder: 7:38.
C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, to Mrs. Henry [Josephine D.] Barnard, 23 August 1848. Box-folder: 7:61.
Henry Barnard, New York, to Charles Campbell, 11 October 1848. Box- folder: 7:65.
Josephine D. Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to Charles Campbell, 8 May 1849. Box-folder: 7:83.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to [Josephine D. Barnard], 16 May 1849. Box-folder: 7:84.
Henry Barnard, Washington, to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 5 January 1853. Box-folder: 9:2.
Henry Barnard, Hartford, Connecticut, to [Charles Campbell], 5 December 1855. Box-folder: 10:19.
Henry Barnard, Washington, to Charles Campbell, 4 March 1869. Box-folder: 14:61.
Draper, Lyman Copeland (1815-1891)
Lyman C. Draper, Baltimore, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 7 April 1846. Box-folder: 5:98.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Lyman C. Draper, 10 April 1846. Box-folder: 5:102.
Lyman C. Draper, Baltimore, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 5 May 1846. Box-folder: 5:117.
Lyman C. Draper, Baltimore, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, [Petersburg], 29 July 1846. Box-folder: 5:141.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Lyman C. Draper, [Baltimore], 3 August 1846. Box-folder: 6:1.
Lyman C. Draper, Baltimore, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 25 August 1846. Box-folder: 6:7.
Lyman C. Draper, Baltimore, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 13 January 1848. Box-folder: 7:4.
Lyman C. Draper, Baltimore, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 6 March 1848. Box-folder: 7:16.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to [Lyman C. Draper, Baltimore], 8 March 1848. Box-folder: 7:18.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Lyman C. Draper, 9 March 1848. Box-folder: 7:19.
Lyman C. Draper, Philadelphia, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 29 July 1848. Box-folder: 7:50.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Lyman C. Draper, [Philadelphia], 7 August 1848. Box-folder: 7:57.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Lyman C. Draper, Philadelphia, 15 June 1849. Box-folder: 7:87.
Lyman C. Draper, Philadelphia, to [Charles Campbell, Petersburg], 26 June 1849. Box-folder: 7:88.
Lyman C. Draper, Leverington, Pennsylvania, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 10 February 1851. Box-folder: 8:34.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to L[yman] C. Draper, 19 February 1851. Box-folder: 8:35.
Lyman C. Draper, Leverington, Pennsylvania, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 12 March 1851. Box-folder: 8:37.
A Notice that Charles Campbell has been elected an Honorary Member of the State Historical Society of Wisconsin, signed by Lyman C. Draper, 4 March 1854. Box-folder: 9:58.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to Lyman C. Draper, [Madison, Wisconsin], 21 March 1854. Box-folder: 9:64.
Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 29 July 1854. Box-folder: 9:79.
Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, 22 February 1859. Box-folder: 11:107.
Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, 25 March 1859. Box-folder: 11:121.
C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, to Lyman C. Draper, [Madison, Wisconsin], 14 April 1859. Box-folder: 11:128.
Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, [Petersburg], 31 March 1868. Box-folder: 14:6.
C[harles] C[ampbell], Petersburg, to Lyman C. Draper, [Madison, Wisconsin], 20 May 1868. Box-folder: 14:12.
Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin, to Charles Campbell, 7 January 1870. Box-folder: 14:76.
Lyman C. Draper, Madison, Wisconsin, to Ch[arle]s Campbell, 16 September 1872. Box-folder: 14:77.
Grigsby, Hugh Blair (1806-1881)
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, Virginia, to Charles Campbell, 3 September 1856. Box-folder: 10:54.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to H[ugh] B. Grigsby, [Norfolk], 17 November 1856. Box-folder: 10:57.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to [Charles Campbell], Petersburg, 6 December 1856. Box-folder: 10:61.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Hugh B. Grigsby, [Norfolk], 9 November 1857. Box-folder: 10:72.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 8 December 1857. Box-folder: 10:74.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, Virginia, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, [before June 1858]. Box-folder: 10:93.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, Virginia, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 27 June 1858. Box-folder: 10:95.
[Charles Campbell], Warrenton, to H[ugh] B. Grigsby, [Charlotte Court House?], 25 July 1858. Box-folder: 10:102.
Charles Campbell, Warrenton, to Hugh B. Grigsby, [Charlotte Court House?], 26 July 1858. Box-folder: 10:104.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, Virginia, to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 27 July 1858. Box-folder: 10:105.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, Virginia, to [Charles Campbell], 12 August 1858. Box-folder: 11:2.
Charles Campbell, Warrenton, to Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse], 22 August 1858. Box-folder: 11:4.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, Virginia, to Charles Campbell, [Petersburg], 30 August 1858. Box-folder: 11:6.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, C[ourt] H[ouse], to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 22 September 1858. Box-folder: 11:14.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to [Hugh B. Grigsby], 8 October 1858. Box-folder: 11:21.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to [Hugh B. Grigsby], 15 October 1858. Box-folder: 11:25.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Hugh B. Grigsby, 18 October 1858. Box-folder: 11:31.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to Hugh B. Grigsby, 18 October 1858. Box-folder: 11:32.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, C[ourt] H[ouse], to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 4 November 1858. Box-folder: 11:40.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 21 January 1859. Box-folder: 11:91.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 2 February 1859. Box-folder: 11:98.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to [Charles Campbell, Petersburg], 12 February 1859. Box-folder: 11:104.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to [Charles Campbell], 2 March 1859. Box-folder: 11:113.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Hugh B. Grigsby, 4 March 1859. Box-folder: 11:114.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 6 March 1859. Box-folder: 11:115.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to Townsend Ward, Philadelphia, 28 March 1859. Box-folder: 11:122.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to C[harles] Campbell, 13 May 1859. Box-folder: 11:130.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte C[ourt] H[ouse], to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 13 August 1859. Box-folder: 11:142.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 24 January 1860. Box-folder: 12:13.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 15 February 1860. Box-folder: 12:23.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Norfolk, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 22 February 1860. Box-folder: 12:28.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, C. H. to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 25 August 1862. Box-folder: 12:84.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, C[ourt] H[ouse] to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 9 April 1867. Box-folder: 13:43.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, C[ourt] H[ouse], to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 24 June 1867. Box-folder: 13:45.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, Virginia to [Charles Campbell], 10 October 1867. Box-folder: 13:76.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Edgehill, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 20 June 1868. Box-folder: 14:22.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, C[ourt] H[ouse] to Charles Campbell, Warrenton, 18 May 1870. Box-folder: 14:81.
[Charles Campbell], Fredericksburg, to Hugh B. Grigsby, 25 May 1870. Box-folder: 14:83.
Hugh B. Grigsby, Charlotte, C[ourt] H[ouse] to Charles Campbell, 31 May 1870. Box-folder: 14:84.
[Charles Campbell], Fredericksburg, to Hugh B. Grigsby, 2 June 1870. Box-folder: 14:85.
Howe, Henry (1816- 1893)
[Henry Howe?], Midlothian, Chesterfield County, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 14 July 1843. [signature clipped]. Box-folder: 4:108.
Henry Howe, New Haven, Connecticut, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 14 September 1844. Box-folder: 5:5.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to Henry Howe, 29 September 1844. Box-folder: 5:6.
Henry Howe, New Haven, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, Virginia, 6 November 1844. Box-folder: 5:10.
Charles Campbell, Richmond, to Henry Howe, 15 November 1844. Box-folder: 5:11.
Henry Howe, New Haven, Connecticut, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, 20 November 1844. Box-folder: 5:12.
Henry Howe, New Haven, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 23 November 1844. Box-folder: 5:15.
Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, to Henry Howe, 11 February 1845. Box-folder: 5:24.
Henry Howe, Richmond, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, 20 April 1845. Box-folder: 5:31.
Henry Howe, New Haven, Connecticut, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Richmond, 3 May 1845. Box-folder: 5:32.
Henry Howe, New Haven, Connecticut, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, 19 November 1845. Box-folder: 5:69.
Henry Howe, Cincinnati, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 24 February 1859. Box-folder: 11:108.
Henry Howe, Cincinnati, to Cha[rle]s Campbell, Petersburg, 8 March 1859. Box-folder: 11:116.
Minor, Benjamin Blake (1818- 1905)
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to B[enjamin] B. Minor, Richmond, 24 July 1840. Box-folder: 4:20.
Benjamin B. Minor, Kenmore, to Charles Campbell, 8 December 1840. Box-folder: 4:30.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to B[enjamin] B. Minor, Richmond, 13 September 1843. Box-folder: 4:115.
B[enjamin] B. Minor, Savannah, to Charles Campbell, Petersburg, 16 February 1844. Box-folder: 4:133.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to Benjamin B. Minor, Richmond, 10 December 1846. Box-folder: 6:33.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to [Benjamin B. Minor, Richmond], 10 December 1846. Box-folder: 6:34.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to B[enjamin] B. Minor, Richmond, 29 December 1846. Box-folder: 6:39.
[Benjamin B.] Minor, to C[harles] Campbell, 11 January 1847. Box-folder: 6:41.
[Benjamin B.] Minor, to [Charles] Campbell, 22 January 1847. Box-folder: 6:44.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to B[enjamin] B. Minor, [Richmond], 24 March 1847. Box-folder: 6:58.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to Benj[amin] B. Minor, 30 March 1847. Box-folder: 6:60.
Charles Campbell, Petersburg, to [Benjamin B. Minor, Richmond], 30 March 1847. Box-folder: 6:61.
[Charles Campbell], Petersburg, to B[enjamin] B. Minor, [Richmond], 15 September 1847. Box-folder: 6:80.
B[enjamin] [B.] Minor, Fredericksburg, to Charles Campbell, Richmond, 4 January 1859. Box-folder: 11:83.